## Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/saurabhskj (LinkedIn) fun2dolabs.org (Company)

# Top Skills

Core Java J2ME HTML 5

## Languages

Japanese (Elementary)
Sanskrit (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)

#### Honors-Awards

Speaker Charter Member

#### **Publications**

Mobile Phone Programming

Mobile Phone Programming Using
Java ME (J2ME)

#### **Patents**

PERSONAL PERSISTENT
MESSAGING SYSTEM
NEURO SYMBOLIC NETWORK
GENERATION AND EXECUTION
SYSTEM

# Saurabh Jain

Vice President, Paytm Central

# Summary

Saurabh is Vice President at Paytm. He is heading the 'Paytm - Build for India' program and also has an active role in startup products, developer relations, social impact / CSR, education and training within Paytm. Saurabh also manages the relationships with various industry bodies including NASSCOM, CII, FICCI, PHDCCI.

Saurabh Jain is also the founder of Fun2Do Labs. Fun2Do Labs believes in the motto - 'Making education OPEN and FUN!'. Fun2Do Labs is an Open Education Project. Fun2Do Labs is pioneering research into transmedia education, maker education and startup education.

Saurabh is a Chartered Accountant with keen interest in technology. Saurabh has authored 2 books on mobile application technology. He wrote 'Mobile Phone Programming', which was India's first book on mobile app programming. The book was published in 2003 and was a technical book on J2ME technology.

He is the inventor of PERSONAL PERSISTENT MESSAGING SYSTEM (PPMS) and NEURO SYMBOLIC NETWORK GENERATION AND EXECUTION SYSTEM for which he had got provisional patents.

Saurabh has been a speaker at following places :

- + SXSW 2019 and SXSW Edu 2018 in USA
- + BlackBerry Jam Europe in Amsterdam
- + BlackBerry Jam Asia in Hong Kong
- + Major startup events by governments of Rajasthan, UP and Uttarakhand
- + Programs by NASSCOM / FICCI / PHDCCI
- + UNESCO MGIEP TECH 2017 education conference
- + IIT Delhi, IIT Roorkee and IIT Patna
- + IIM Ahmedabad, IIM Lucknow, IIM Visakhapatnam, IIM Rohtak and IIM Kashipur

+ SRCC and many others in Delhi University, Symbiosis, Narsee Monjee, Amity, VIT, SRM and lots of other institutions and conferences

He is a charter member of TiE. As a software developer he has been awarded the following titles in the past - 'BlackBerry Elite' and 'Nokia Developer Champion'. He has also been selected as an 'Indian Leader for Social Sector' by ILSS. Saurabh is an avid reader and has read more than 175 books in last 4 years.

# Experience

Paytm

2 years 10 months

Vice President

June 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Noida Area, India

Heading CSR initiatives

Heading Paytm - Build for India initiative

Head: 'Paytm - Build for India'

November 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months)

New Delhi Area, India

We require everybody to be a lifelong learner in the digital age. The current education system unfortunately does not achieve this goal. I am devoting my life to help turn everyone into a lifelong learner.

Would like to thank Mr. Vijay Shekhar Sharma, Founder, Paytm for giving me an opportunity to achieve this goal through 'Paytm - Build for India' initiative

Fun2Do Labs

Founder

September 2016 - Present (4 years)

New Delhi Area, India

Fun2Do Labs is an Open Education project. We believe in 'Making education OPEN and FUN!'.

Delhi Press

Mentor

February 2016 - Present (4 years 7 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Mentoring the management, editorial and tech teams at Delhi Press on digital technology and mobile apps.

### SKJ Technologies Private Ltd

Director

October 2009 - Present (10 years 11 months)

Founder of CraftSlide suite of mobile games and apps

Founder of OpenClass - Community of mobile app developers

SKJ Technologies (A unit of Swatantar Associates Pvt Ltd)

Director

April 2002 - September 2009 (7 years 6 months)

SKJ Technologies (A unit of Swatantar Associates Pvt Ltd) was one of the first companies in India to venture into mobile game and application development way back in 2002.

The company was a direct supplier of mobile games to Reliance

Communications Ltd and direct supplier of mobile games and other mobile

VAS content to Tata Teleservices Ltd and Tata Teleservices (Maharashtra)

Ltd.

The company also supplied games to many large names in the mobile industry. The company was also active in the area of J2ME / Java ME learning.

Base 77

Consultant

April 2006 - August 2006 (5 months)

Base77 is an offshore software, multimedia, and web development company with strong expertise in robust, user-friendly, cost-effective, reliable, and firm IT solutions and services; ranging from simple to complex, across a broad spectrum of technologies and diverse domains.

I helped Base77 to set up its mobile games and applications unit. I taught their team, skills for mobile game development and Java ME / J2ME. I also helped them to market there games and applications in the initial phase.

Education

## Institute of Chartered Accountants of India

CA, Accounts, Audit, Tax Laws and Information Technology · (1999 - 2003)

## **ARSD**

B.Com (Hons), Commerce · (1998 - 2001)

# Modern School

Primary and High School Degree, Schooling (Nursery to 12th) · (1985 - 1998)